Guide to the Boniface I. Obichere papers, 1959-1996
Obichere, Boniface I. papers, 1959-1996
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Boniface I. Obichere papers, 1959-1996
6481
Boniface I. Obichere, 1932-1997
29.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, notebooks, book manuscripts, scholarly journals, letters of recommendation, student papers, course materials, conference papers, reports, grant materials, committee papers, maps, photographs, slides, audio recordings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, notes, and writings of Boniface Obichere, a UCLA professor of African history. Includes student and class papers, along with materials from various committees and organizations in which Obichere participated, particularly UCLA's African Study Center and the Journal of African Studies.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Boniface Ihewunwa Obichere was born on November 4, 1932 in Awaka, Owerri, Nigeria, the son of Ibari Ikeri and Eke Ogbuagu. He attended Roman Catholic primary schools and the local teachers college before working as an elementary school teacher in Nigeria. After resettling in the United States, he received a Bachelor of Arts (1961) and a Masters of Arts (1963) from the University of Minnesota. He married Armer Gean Brown on August 22, 1964, and with her had one son, Chikere Igbolelenwa.
Boniface Obichere earned his D. Phil from Oxford University, England in 1967 and later that year became an acting assistant professor at the University of California at Los Angeles (UCLA). By 1969 he had earned the rank of associate professor and by 1973 that of full professor. He taught both undergraduate and graduate level African history courses for thirty years and was the advisor to numerous masters and doctoral students.
Obichere specialized in West African history with a particular focus on African military history, African and African-American relations, African political leadership, Pan-Africanism, and the history of Nigeria, Asante, and Dahomey. In addition to numerous articles, book chapters, and reviews, he authored the book West African States and European Expansion: The Dahomey-Niger Hinterland, 1885-1898 (1971) and edited Studies in Southern Nigerian History (1982) and African States and the Military: Past and Present (1988).
Obichere also actively participated in UCLA committees and outside organizations that covered his areas of interests. From 1972-1978 he served as the director of the UCLA African Studies Center and afterwards sat on its Faculty Advisory Committee. In 1974, he was the founding editor of the Journal of African Studies, a scholarly journal published by the African Studies Center, and in addition, worked on the editorial board of the Journal of Black Studies, AMAN, UMOJA: A Scholarly Journal of Black Studies, and the Ibadan Humanities Journal. He was a member of numerous academic organizations and served as the director of the African Studies Association, and as a board member of such organizations as Operations Crossroads Africa; the L.S.B. Leakey Foundation; the African Institute for the Study of Human Values; and the Association for the Advancement of Policy, Research and Development. He participated in the United Nations Economic Conference for Africa and was also active in charitable causes, such as the Biafra Children's Relief Committee. He was a visiting professor at the University of Hawaii (1969-1970), the University of Ghana (1970-1971), and the University of Ilorin, Nigeria (1979-1980).
During a career that lasted 30 years, Obichere won numerous awards including a 1991 Golden Star Halo Award given by the Southern California Motion Picture Council for his work on a series produced for PBS called "Israel and Black Africa." That same year, the Liberian Studies Association awarded him a lifetime achievement award for his work in African Studies. Boniface Obichere died of prostate cancer six years later on March 14, 1997.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
This collection consists of Boniface I. Obichere's professional papers, documenting his career as an UCLA African history professor, an author, and an editor. The papers include correspondence; student and class files; professional reviews and recommendations; papers from various conferences; papers used as editor of the Journal of African Studies, with submissions to that journal; and both Obichere's own book manuscripts and those of other authors. The papers also contain material pertaining to UCLA's African Studies Center (now the James S. Coleman African Studies Center), including newsletters, reports, committee papers, grant information, and papers created by various colloquiums and conferences hosted by the Center. The collection documents numerous organizations and committees in which Obichere participated, in particular: the Biafra Children's Relief Committee/Peace in Biafra; the L.S.B Leakey Foundation; Operation Crossroads Africa; UCLA's Committee on International and Comparative Studies; UCLA's Education Abroad Program to Africa and its Ad hoc Advisory Committee; UCLA's Senate Equal Opportunity Committee/Academic Affirmative Action Compliance Committee; and the United Nations Economic Council for Africa, Conference of African Planners. Maps, photographs, postcards, cassette and reel-to-reel tapes are also incorporated.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Biafra Children's Relief Fund.; Joint Conference of African Planners, Statisticians, and Demographers.; L.S.B. Leakey Foundation.; Operation Crossroads Africa.; United Nations.; University of California, Los Angeles. Academic Affirmative Action Compliance Committee.; University of California, Los Angeles. Committee on International and Comparitive Studies.; University of California, Los Angeles. Dept. of History.; University of California, Los Angeles. Education Abroad Program.; University of California, Los Angeles. Faculty.; University of California, Los Angeles. James S. Coleman African Studies Center.; University of California, Los Angeles. Senate Equal Opportunity Committee.
Subjects:
Authors, Nigerian.; Ethnology--Nigeria.; Nigerian American men.
Places:
Africa--History--20th century.; Africa--Study and teaching.; Ashanti (Kingdom).; Nigeria--History.
Form and Genre Terms:
Audiotapes.; Maps.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Student papers (boxes 6-14), professional reviews and recommendations (boxes 12, 14-15), and grant materials (boxes 29, 31) are all restricted.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical/Personal
Boxes 1-2, map case
Series II. Correspondence
Boxes 2-5
Series III. Students and Teaching
a. Class Files
Boxes 1, 5-9
b. Student Files
Boxes 7, 9-14
c. Professional Reviews/Recommendations
Boxes 12, 14-15
Series IV. Written works
a. Obichere's Works
Boxes 1, 5, 16-17
b. Other Authors' Manuscripts
Boxes 5, 17-20
c. Publications
Boxes 19-22, 38-39
d. Conference Materials
Boxes 19, 21, 23, 39
Series V. Journal of African Studies
a. General
Boxes 4-5, 21, 23
b. Submissions
Boxes 21, 23-24
c. Journal of African Studies
Boxes 24-25
Series VI. African Studies Center
a. General
Box 25
b. Budget
Box 25
c. Committees
Boxes 23, 27, 29
d. Reports
Box 25
e. Publications
Box 25
f. Events: Colloquiums, Symposiums, Conferences, Lectures
Box 23, 25-26
Series VII. Committees, Programs, Projects
Boxes 14-15, 23, 26-30
Series VIII. Grants
a. Ford Foundation
Box 29
b. Institute of American Culture
Boxes 29, 31
c. National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH)
Box 31
d. Office of Education, National Defense Education Fund
Box 31
e. UCLA and African Studies Center Grants
Box 31
f. Miscellaneous Grants
Box 31
Series IX. Notes and Notebooks
Boxes 28, 30
Series X. Audio and Visual Materials
a. Maps
Box 36, map case
b. Photographs, Slides, and Postcards
Boxes 30, 22-33
c. Audio and Video Recordsings
Boxes 33-34
d. Textile Objects
Box 35, map case
e. Ephemera
Boxes 32-33, map case
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical/Personal
  - Biographies, publications lists, certificates, 1973-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Traveler's Handbook" (address book), ca.1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letterhead and business cards (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Real estate papers: Brochures and notes (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Real estate papers: Notes, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Legal papers: Foreclosure and bankruptcy, 1984-1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Driver's license, social security card, W-2 forms, 1974-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Blueprint for Obichere's house in Awaka, Nigeria, 1972 (Folder 1)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Correspondence: General, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: General, 1968 Jan.-Oct. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: General, 1968 Nov.-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: General, 1969 Jan.-Feb. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: General, 1969 Mar.-Apr. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: General, 1969 May (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: General, 1969 June-July (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: General, 1969 Aug. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: General, 1969 Sept. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: General, 1969 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: General, 1969 Nov. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: General, 1969 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: General, 1970 Jan. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: General, 1970 Feb. 3-10 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: General, 1970 Feb. 11-28 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: General, 1970 Mar. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: General, 1970 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: General, 1970 May-Aug. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: General, 1970 Oct.-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: General, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: General, 1972 Jan.-May (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: General, 1972 June-July (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: General, 1972 Aug.-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: General, 1973 Jan.-Feb. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: General, 1973 Mar. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: General, 1973 Apr.-May (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: General, 1973 June-July (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: General, 1973 Aug.-Oct. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: General, 1973 Oct.-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: General, 1974 Jan.-Mar. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: General, 1974 Apr.-May (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: General, 1974 June-Sept. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: General, 1974 Oct.-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: General, 1975 Jan.-Mar. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: General, 1975 Apr.-May (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: General, 1975 June-Aug. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: General, 1975 Sept.-Oct. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: General, 1975 Nov.-Dec. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: General, 1976 Jan.-Feb. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: General, 1976 Mar. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: General, 1976 Apr.-May (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: General, 1976 June (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: General, 1976 July (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: General, 1976 Aug.-Dec. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: General, 1977 Jan.-Oct. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: General, 1977 Nov.-Dec. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: General, 1978 Jan.-Feb. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: General, 1978 Mar.-Apr. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: General, 1978 May-Aug. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: General, 1978 Sept.-Dec. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: General, 1979 Jan.-Mar. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: General, 1979 Apr.-June (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: General, 1979 July-Dec. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: General, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: General, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: General, 1983 Jan.-July (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: General, 1983 Aug.-Dec. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: General, 1984 Jan.-Mar. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: General, 1984 Apr.-July (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: General, 1984 Aug.-Dec. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: General, 1985 Jan.-Mar. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: General, 1985 Apr.-May (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: General, 1985 June-Sept. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: General, 1985 Oct.-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: General, 1986 Jan.-May (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: General, 1986 June-Sept. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: General, 1986 Oct.-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: General, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: General, 1988 Jan.-Mar. 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: General, 1988 Mar. 14-Aug. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: General, 1988 Sept.-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: General, 1989 Jan.-July (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: General, 1989 Aug.-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: General, 1990 Jan.-Oct. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: General, 1990 Nov.-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: General, 1991 Jan.-July (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: General, 1991 Aug.-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: General, 1992 Jan.-Apr. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: General, 1992 May-Aug. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: General, 1992 Sept.-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: General, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: General, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: General, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: General, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: General (Box 4, Folder 24-26)
  - Correspondence: Akinkugbe, Professor O.O., 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Books/articles reviewed, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Book reviews, 1975-1982, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Cannon, Alfred, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Chipembere Trust Fund, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Friedmann, John, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: Journal of African Studies, 1969-1974 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: Journal of African Studies, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: Journal of African Studies, 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Journal of African Studies, 1981-1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Kagombe, Maina, editor-in-chief, Pan-African Journal, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Merriam, Alan P., 1968-1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Nok Publishers, Ltd., 1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Obichere, Isaac, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Obichere, Oliver, 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Opara, Theodore, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Publications, 1972-1973 Feb (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Publications, 1973 Mar.-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Publications, 1974 Jan.-Aug. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Publications, 1974 Sept.-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Publications, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Publications, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Publications of Dr. Obichere, 1971-1973 Aug. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Publications of Dr. Obichere, 1973 Sept.-1976 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Series III. Students and Teaching
  - Class Files
    - History 10B, Introduction to the Civilizations of Africa
      - History 10B: Syllabi and textbook orders, 1974-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - History 10B: Study guide and work book, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - History 10B: Reserve readings, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
      - History 10B: Reserve readings, 1993, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - History 10B: Test questions and assignments, 1979-1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - History 10B: Student papers and tests [RESTRICTED], 1979-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - History 10B: Class rosters and grade lists [RESTRICTED], 1979-1996, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - History 10B: Course evaluations [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - History 99, The Philosophy and Methodology of History
      - History 99: Syllabi and handouts, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - History 99: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1995 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
      - History 99: Class rosters and grade lists [RESTRICTED], 1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - History 101, Introduction to Historical Practice
      - History 101: Syllabi and book information, 1987-1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - History 101: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - History 101: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1994 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - History 101: Class rosters [RESTRICTED], 1994 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - History 125A, History of Africa to 1800
      - History 125A: Syllabi and reading lists, 1968-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - History 125A: Test questions, 1967-1977, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - History 125A/B: Student notebook, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - History 125A: Student tests [RESTRICTED], 1967, 1969, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - History 125A: Student tests [RESTRICTED], 1975 (Box 6, Folder 9-12)
      - History 125A: Class rosters and grade lists [RESTRICTED], 1967-1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - History 125A: Enrollment cards [RESTRICTED], n.d. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - History 125B, History of Tropical Africa in the 19th and 20th Centuries
      - History 125B: Syllabi and test questions, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - History 125B: Student tests and class rosters [RESTRICTED], 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - History 125C, History of Africa in the Twentieth Century
      - History 125C: Syllabi, reading lists, and test questions, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - History 125C: Student tests and papers [RESTRICTED], 1969, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - History 125C: Student tests and papers [RESTRICTED], 1973 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
      - History 125C: Student tests and papers [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - History 125C: Student tests and papers [RESTRICTED] (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - History 125C: Registration slips [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - History 126A/B, History of West Africa
      - History 126A/B: Syllabi and test questions, 1970-1978, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - History 126A/B: Student tests [RESTRICTED], 1972, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - History 126A/B: Class rosters and grade lists [RESTRICTED], 1968-1978, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - History 126A: Course evaluations [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - History 175A
      - History 175A: Book report (student paper) [RESTRICTED], n.d. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - History 175B, Africa and the Slave Trade
      - History 175B: Syllabi, course descriptions, and textbook orders, 1986-1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - History 175B: Test questions, 1985-1995, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - History 175B: Book reports (student papers) [RESTRICTED], 1995 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - History 175B: Student papers and tests [RESTRICTED], 1986, 1988, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - History 175B: Class rosters and grade lists [RESTRICTED], 1985-1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - History 175B: Class evaluations [RESTRICTED], 1986 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - History 175C, Africa in the Age of Imperialism, 1875-1960
      - History 175C: Syllabi and textbook orders, 1984-1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - History 175C: Test questions, 1984-1988, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - History 175C: Student tests [RESTRICTED], 1995, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - History 175C: Class rosters and grade lists [RESTRICTED], 1986, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - History 175E, Africa Since 1945
      - History 175E: Syllabi and book orders, 1985-1992, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - History 175E: Test questions, 1987-1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - History 175E: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - History 175E: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - History 175E: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - History 175E: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1996 (Box 6, Folder 29-30)
      - History 175E: Class rosters [RESTRICTED], 1994 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - History 175E: Grades [RESTRICTED], 1987-1995, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - History 175E: Course evaluations [RESTRICTED], 1991 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - History 176A, West Africa from Earliest Times to 1800
      - History 176A: Syllabi, textbook orders, test questions, 1979-1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - History 176A: Handouts (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - History 176A: Course rosters and grade lists [RESTRICTED], 1979-1991 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - History 176A: Course evaluations [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - History 176B, History of West Africa Since 1800
      - History 176B: Syllabi, textbook orders, test questions, and handouts, 1983-1996, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - History 176B: Student tests [RESTRICTED], 1982, 1988, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - History 176B: Student tests [RESTRICTED], 20 Mar. 1996 (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
      - History 176B: Student tests [RESTRICTED], n.d. [20 Mar. 1996] (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - History 176B: Class rosters and grade lists [RESTRICTED], 1983-1996, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - History 176C, Social and Economic History of West Africa
      - History 176C: Syllabi, course descriptions, textbook orders, test questions, 1986-1893 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - History 176C: Student tests [RESTRICTED], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - History 176C: Grade lists [RESTRICTED], 1985-1991, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - History 197, Undergraduate Colloquia
      - History 197: Syllabi, reading lists, and book orders, 1971-1992 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - History 197: Student tests [RESTRICTED], 1969, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - History 197: Student tests [RESTRICTED], 1985, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - History 197: Student tests [RESTRICTED], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - History 197: Student paper [RESTRICTED], 1972 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - History 197: Class lists [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - History 197M: Course evaluations [RESTRICTED], 1983 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - History 197H: Course evaluations [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - History 199, Special Studies
      - History 199: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1969-1974 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - History 199: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1985 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - History 199: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1987 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - History 199: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1988 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - History 199: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1989 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - History 199: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1989, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - History 199: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1995 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - History 199: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1996, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - History 199: Student papers [RESTRICTED], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - History 199: Student papers-Tutoring project [RESTRICTED], 1972 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - History 199: Tutor evaluations [RESTRICTED], 1972 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - History 199: Class rosters, petitions for enrollment, grade lists [RESTRICTED], 1967-1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - History 200N, Advanced Historiography: Africa
      - History 200N: Syllabi, course descriptions, textbook orders, 1982-1996, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - History 200N: Student papers [RESTRICTED], 1982-1995 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - History 200N: Student bibliographies [RESTRICTED], 1995-1996, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - History 200N: Class rosters and grade lists [RESTRICTED], 1988, 1992, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - History 200N: Course evaluations [RESTRICTED], 1982 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - History 201N, Topics in African History
      - History 201N: Syllabi, reading lists, test questions, 1983-1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)